漫威公司出品
瑞典斯德哥尔摩  赛格尔广场
人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译 双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：大卫熊  Silence  点点点  欧阳  胖兔纯
■
翻译：王大可  圈圈  西之  卫老哥  冰蓝
时间轴：雪贵人  贝壳  小萌    校对：米小勒   大卫熊
后期：瓜瓜     总监：米小勒
神盾局特工
第一季 第四集
也许我该学学开飞机
Maybe I should learn to fly.
还不晚  对吧  我可以学
It's not too late, right? I could learn.
你最喜欢开飞机的哪个优点  享受自由
What do you like best -- the freedom?
欣赏风景
The view?
可以独处
The solitude.
明白
Got it.
瑞典见
See you in Sweden.
我只有一次机会开枪
I only get one shot.
在出其意料的同时并将其击倒
And it has to knock a person back, as well as out.
所以我们需要完善这个美丽的玩意
Which is why we're perfecting this little beauty.
点45口径子弹  半自动  每个弹夹
.45-caliber cartridges, semi-automatic. Each mag...
装有八颗装载治疗性绝境病毒的子弹
contains eight therapeutic rounds of dendrotoxin.
以防你没打中
In case you miss!
或是有多名攻击者
Or have multiple assailants.
是的  我们会尽快让这款"好梦"手枪
Yeah, w-we're gonna have this new night-night pistol
准备就绪的
working in no time.
-好吗  -好极了
- Okay? - Great.
有件事
One thing --
那枪不能叫那个名字
we're not calling it that.
早就跟你说了
Ah, told you.
不不  我们就叫这个名字
Yes, we -- yes, we are.
看到斯凯了吗
Have you seen Skye?
武器训练结束后就没见到了
Not since weapons training.
每次扣动扳机后  她还是说"砰"吗
Has she stopped saying "Bang" when she pulls the trigger?
大部分时候吧
Mostly.
现在  如果她能学会枪械的"脱开安全器"
Now, if she can just learn the difference
和"发行杂志"的区别[release单词的不同含义]
between the safety release and the magazine release,
我们就算有进展了
We'll be making real progress.
什么事  菲尔
What's up, Phil?
我希望你别叫我菲尔
I'd prefer you not call me "Phil."
好吧  你是老大  AC[科尔森特工的缩写]
Okay, you're the boss...A.C.
只是有点想念我的货车  想一个人待会儿
Just missing my van a bit, taking a little me time.
我需要你的帮助
I want your help with something.
说吧
Hit me with it.
-你抢过银行吗  -没有
- You ever rob a bank? - No.
-武装汽车呢  -也没有
- An armored car? - Nope.
-那赌场呢  -你是在鄙视我吗
- How about a casino? - Should I be offended?
有人偷了价值千万元的钻石
Somebody's stealing millions of dollars in diamonds.
他们想出了破解安保系统的办法
They've found a way to crack the security systems.
我要你研究出他们怎么做到的
I want you to figure out their exploit.
昨天  55名军人
Yesterday, 55 men, all military,
受雇于全球最牛的珠宝经纪人
were hired by one of the largest gem brokers in the world.
他们穿着一样的衣服
They dressed the men in identical outfits,
随机给他们一人一个手提箱
Gave each one a randomly assigned briefcase,
将他们派往斯德哥尔摩25条不同的路线
and sent them along 25 different routes here in Stockholm.
没人知道哪个手提箱中有钻石
No one knew which briefcase contained the diamonds,
但还是被偷了
But they were still stolen.
谢谢[瑞典语]
Tack.
为什么搞这么复杂
Why the Kabuki theater?
因为最近有人专偷钻石
They were afraid because somebody's targeting diamonds --
米兰的装甲车被偷
an armored car in Milan,
蒙特卡洛的保险箱被盗  现在又是这起
A safe in Monte Carlo, and now this --
总值超过3000万的钻石
Over $30 mil total.
每起都是在安保严密的情况下完成的
Each theft occurred despite heavy security.
听起来像是内部人干的
They sound like inside jobs.
很多人也这样想
A lot of people share that opinion.
看来你不是
You don't.
监控录像有拍到任何行动的录像吗
CCTV cameras catch any of the action?
菲兹·西蒙斯在查
Fitz-Simmons is checking.
系统失效了一个小时
The system went dark for an hour.
他们认为系统被黑了
They think it was hacked.
每次都是同一批人吗
It was the same thieves each time?
是的  但作案的只有一个  一个女人
Yes, but it was just one thief -- a woman.
而且她是在全程闭眼的情况下做到的
And she did it all with her eyes closed.
证人确认她的相貌特征了吗
Eyewitnesses I.D. her?
黑人  体型健美  30岁左右
Black, athletic build, late 20s, early 30s.
你是问她怎么破解这个系统的
So, you asked how she could have cracked the system.
我有个想法  但可能比较离奇
I have a pitch, but it's way outside the box.
我就活在离奇世界里
I live outside the box.
这世界上有的人有超能力  是吗
There are people in the world with superpowers, right?
如果这个女人有超感官知觉呢
What if this woman has ESP or something?
没有可靠的研究报告来证明预知能力
There are no credible studies that support precognition,
心灵感应  或是超感官知觉
telepathy, or extrasensory perception.
所以从科学的观点行不通
Okay, so science says no.
可这个女人知道一些离奇的事
But this woman knew impossible things.
那为什么她闭上眼睛
And why did she close her eyes?
要么是碰巧  要么就是非常重要
That's either random or totally important.
她是在听
Was she listening...
还是在读心
or was she reading minds?
现在我去玩手机了
I'm gonna go play with my phone now.
为什么总部叫我们调查这些抢劫案
Why does H.Q. want us to investigate these heists?
不是总部  是我要接手的
They don't. I picked this up.
-有什么发现吗  -有  手机信号满格
- Any luck?  - Yep, I'm getting full bars,
假设我当时在这里
which means if I was down here
有55个带着红色恐怖面具的人
and 55 guys were in scary red masks,
你知道我会怎么做吗
you know what I would do?
玩图片分享
Instagram.
花园
很厉害
It's amazing.
每年我们这方面的工作变得更容易
Every year, this part of our job gets easier.
在脸谱网  图片分享和网络相册当中
Between FaceBbook, Instagram, and Flickr,
大家就是自己的监视器
people are surveilling themselves.
用许多过滤器来选择
With many filters to choose from.
当我为涨潮组织做黑客时
I could do this pretty well
我对此很在行
when I was hacking for the Rising Tide,
但你们连接和搜索
but you guys tag and search
在某种程度上是我们无法想象的
in ways the rest of us never dreamed of.
我可以在这些照片上使用脸部识别软件
I can run facial-recognition software on the photos,
和我们的犯罪数据库交叉引用
cross-reference them with our criminal databases.
不必这么做
You don't have to.
这就是那个小偷
That's the thief.
她叫阿奇拉·阿玛多尔
Her name's Akela Amador.
你确定吗
You're certain?
应该  我培训过她
I should be. I trained her.
阿奇拉·阿玛多尔曾是一名神盾局特工
Akela Amador was a S.H.I.E.L.D. agent.
七年前  她对凡切特的劳改营发动了袭击
Seven years ago, she led a raid on one of Vanchat's gulags.
大家都认为
Everyone believed that
她和另外两名特工在任务中牺牲
she and the two other agents on the mission were killed.
我怀疑过
I had my doubts.
我派了第二小队去查看  以防万一
So I sent in a second team, just in case.
他们发现了遗骸
They found a lot of carnage
但无法确认是否是阿玛多尔的
but couldn't confirm that any of it was Amador --
也留下了想象的可能性
Left the possibility open.
所以当你听说这起抢劫案
That's why you chose this op --
你选择要跟进这项调查是吧
when you heard about the heists.
这世界上只有少数女性
There are only a few women in the world
可以完成如此不可能的事
who could pull off something so impossible.
既然你在空客上  我想应该是她
Since you're on the bus, I thought it had to be her.
瑞典海关确认阿玛多尔离开了瑞典
Swedish customs confirmed that Amador left the country
在瑞典护照上用的是化名
using an alias on a Swedish passport.
她飞往白俄罗斯
She flew into Belarus,
买了张火车票去了个叫做兹洛达的小镇
bought a train ticket to a town called Zloda.
我同时也把一份
I've also put together
有可能收买那批钻石的人员清单列了出来
a list of individuals who could fence that many diamonds.
一直没有两者间进一步的接触或行动
There's been no contact or activity.
也许她是留作急需之用吧
Maybe she's saving them for a rainy day,
用来买一些特别的东西
buying something special.
把注意力都放在阿玛多尔身上
Let's focus on finding Amador.
我要告知总部  她还活着
I'll let H.Q. know she's alive
好让他们能协助追捕
so they can assist with the manhunt.
我想推迟一会
I'd like to hold off on that.
直到我们得到更多信息
Until we know more.
联系白俄罗斯当局
Contact Belarus authorities.
找个地方让我们停"空客"
Find us a place to park the bus.
将兹洛达附近的旅馆  酒店
Put together a list of inns, hotels,
以及养老院列出来
and pensions near Zloda.
数量应该不多
There can't be that many of them.
我们会找到她的
We'll find her.
到头来  我也不是那么特别嘛
I'm not so special after all.
我并非你的第一个徒弟
I'm not your first protege.
别紧张  开个玩笑
Relax. I'm teasing.
我知道我不算是徒弟
I know I'm not a protege.
我甚至还不能算是真正的神盾局特工
Hell, I'm not even a real, live S.H.I.E.L.D. agent yet.
你们俩完全不一样
You two couldn't be more different.
阿玛多尔很聪明  很有本事  很勇敢
Amador was smart, talented, fearless.
和我真是天渊之别啊
Wow, there's nothing in common.
让我把话说完
Let me finish.
她和其他人相处得并不好
She didn't play well with others,
觉得团队合作没意义
found little value in teamwork.
我以为我可以给她灌输那些品质
I thought I could instill those qualities in her,
所以我鞭策她...
so I pushed her...
或许是有点过火了
maybe too hard.
别因为这女人走上邪途而自责
Don't blame yourself because this chick went to the dark side.
不管她走怎样的路
Whatever path she went down,
涉足什么奇怪的事  这都是她的问题
whatever weird stuff she got into, it's on her.
协议上说了单独见面
The agreement was to come alone.
-我一个人啊  -那隔壁房间的人呢
- I did! - What about the man in the next room?
还有楼梯那里的那位
Or the one by the stairs?
他们是来这里保护我...
They're here to protect me for when I leave...
护送货品离开的
with the merchandise.
求求你
Please.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我以前从没做过这种事
I've never done this before.
我可以看一下吗
May I see them?
-其他的在...  -在包里
- The rest -- they are... - In the bag.
你可以带着它过海关
You can carry it through customs.
没人会发现的
No one will know.
现在
Now...
轮到你了
It's your turn.
我开价三千万的时候
When I said $30 million,
从没想过有人会...
I never thought anybody would --
如果这是假的
If it fails,
你等着瞧吧
I will find you.
按照约定  拥有所有的权限
It will access all the levels, as promised.
但一旦你进去了
But once you're inside,
你想好计划了吗
do you have a plan?
到时就想好了
It'll come to me.
白俄罗斯  兹洛达
好兴奋啊
How exciting.
上学的时候我就梦想着要来兹洛达
I've dreamed of visiting Zloda since I was a schoolgirl.
白俄罗斯的兹洛达吗
Zloda, Belarus?
梦想成真  你说真的吗
A dream come true? Really?
这是诺贝尔物理学奖得主若列斯·阿尔费罗夫的
It's the birthplace of Nobel Physicist
出生地啊
Zhores Alferov.
严格上讲  他出生在维捷布斯克
I mean, technically, he's from Vitebsk,
但离这里只有一小时不到的车程
But that's less than an hour from here,
你居然不知道  这让我有点失望啊
and I'm a bit disappointed that you didn't know that.
不  我当然知道他是谁
Well, no, of course I know who that is,
半导体异质结构之父
father of heterostructure transistors,
谢谢提醒
thank you very much.
我们都知道
We're all well aware of that.
我只是有点心事重重
I'm just a little bit preoccupied.
我们上一次出外勤任务
Our first and only other time in the field
很糟糕  不是吗
wasn't exactly a picnic, was it?
你们俩只是来这里用电子的方法寻找阿玛多尔
You guys are only here to search for amador electronically.
你们甚至连车都不用下
You won't even need to leave the van.
-空客呼叫小客  -这里是小客
- Bus to Short Bus. - Go for Short Bus.
下次让我来给我们自己定代号  知道吗
Next time, I'll decide what we call ourselves, okay?
总部那边让我们汇报情况
H.Q. Has requested a status update.
你怎么跟他们说的
What'd you tell them?
说我们在追查一个潜在的疑犯  没说别的
That we're tracking a potential suspect -- nothing more.
我欠你一个人情
I owe you one.
三个人情了好吗
More like three.
如果阿玛多尔在这里  她肯定会联系买家
If Amador's here, she'll have to contact her buyer.
扫描手机传输信号
Scan for cellphone transmissions,
加密邮件  匿名广播签名
encrypted E-mails, anomalous broadcast signatures.
一旦发现她的踪迹就呼叫我们
Call us if you find anything that indicates her presence.
除非万不得已  保持无线电静默
Maintain radio silence unless you really need help.
呃  万不得已的定义是什么
Well, what exactly defines needing help?!
长官  我只能想象  被你亲自训练出来...
I can only imagine how painful this must be for you, sir...
而且信任的人背叛  一定让你很痛苦
betrayed by someone you trained and believed in.
我们还不清楚实情
We don't have all the facts yet.
确实  但我不得不假设最坏的情况...
True, but I have to assume the worst...
就是阿玛多尔出卖了任务中的另两名特工
that Amador sold out the other two agents on her mission.
我好奇她得到了什么作为交换
Wonder what she got in exchange.
我不知道  但是在我们搞清楚之前
I don't know, but until we do,
我不做任何假设
I'm not gonna assume anything.
这个小镇都没什么电力
There's barely electricity in this town.
找到我们这位神秘女郎应该不会太难
Can't be too hard to find our mystery woman.
除非她已经知道了我们在这里
Unless she already knows we're here.
不  你不是在暗示某种未卜先知
No, you're not suggesting some sort of precognition
或者心灵感应之类的  因为...
or telepathy because...
我知道  因为不存在
I know...it doesn't exist.
在不久前  我还会把超感官知觉这种说辞
And not long ago, I would have dumped ESP
归档为外星人和传送门一类的疯子想法中
in the "Aliens and portals are for crazy people" pile.
不过现在...
But now...
发现一台服务器
Found a server.
成功接入本地服务器
谢谢[俄语]
Спасибо.
-找到阿玛多尔了吗  -什么
- Did you locate Amador?   -  What?
没  还没有
No, not yet.
不过我们发现一段广播
But we've found a broadcast
有奇怪的信号被加密在里面
with some weird signal encrypted into it.
你认为阿玛多尔可能会通过这段信号通信吗
You think Amador might be communicating on that signal?
也许  不过我呼叫是因为有一个
Maybe, but I called with
同样紧急的问题问你  我的监管人员
an equally pressing question for you, my S.O.
如果我们想嘘嘘该怎么办
What are we supposed to do if we have to pee?
你违反规定就因为需要解个手吗
You broke protocol because you need a bathroom break?
路途真的非常远  每个人又都很紧张
It was a really, really long drive, and everyone's nervous.
蓝色箱子的底部有一个容器
There's a container in the bottom of the blue chest.
蓝色箱子的底部
Bottom of the blue chest.
不会是那个水瓶子吧
Not the water bottle?
就是它
That's the one.
你难道从没学过
Did you never learn the thing
男生和女生的身体部件不同
that boy parts and girl parts are different,
而我们的部件不是小鸡鸡吗
and our parts aren't penises?
科尔森特工和我正努力在找一个危险的罪犯
Agent Coulson and I are trying to find a dangerous criminal.
如果没有其他的紧急事件的话...
If there's nothing else pressing...
好吧  那个  菲兹想知道你带小吃了没有
Well, listen, Fitz wants to know if you packed any snacks.
因为我有点饿了
'Cause I'm feeling a bit peckish.
喂  喂...
Hello? He...
他挂了
he hung up.
-下午好[俄语]  -下午好
- Добрый день. - Good afternoon.
我是科尔森特工  这位是沃德特工
I'm Agent Coulson. This is Agent Ward.
我们在找这位年轻的女士
We're looking for this young woman.
她是我的天使
Oh, she's my angel.
你为什么这么说
Why do you say that?
她有种天赋  她知道一切
She has gift...knows things.
她告诉我去看医生
She told me to go to doctor.
医生发现一枚肿瘤  我下周就要手术了
He found a tumor. I'm having surgery next week.
这个女孩救了我
This girl saved me.
我没法稳定信号
I can't stabilize it.
有一个本地的加密信号在对抗
There's an encrypted local signal competing.
把信号镜像过来
Mirror it over.
我有些涨潮组织漏洞利用工具也许能帮上忙
I have a couple of Rising Tide exploits that might work.
还差一步
One last thing.
搞定  不用谢
Ta-da, and you're welcome.
有重要的事情我们需要找她谈谈
It's very important that we talk with her.
她有天赋  我可以肯定她知道你们来了
With her gift, I'm sure she knows you're coming.
俄罗斯的电视节目有点无聊啊
Russian TV is kind of boring.
这个看起来有点像我们的货车
That looks a bit like our van.
我们看的这是什么
What are we looking at?
我们自己
Us.
我们快出去
Let's get out of here!
该死的高个子
Oh, stupid tall person.
打给科尔森  把枪给我
Call Coulson. Get the gun.
是她
It's her.
扳开保险
Safety off.
砰
Bang?
长官  阿玛多尔攻击了我们
Sir, Amador attacked you and your people.
我们的善意接近她一点都不领情
Whatever regard you hold for her isn't reciprocated.
她打得我们满地找牙
She just kicked us in the teeth.
大家还好吗
How's the team?
受到了惊吓  但所幸没有受伤
Rattled. No broken bones.
还好她是为了逃跑
We're lucky she just knocked the van over
所以只是把货车撞翻了
so she could get away.
估计得好一阵他们才能缓过劲来
Probably take awhile for our folks to refocus.
我想我可以恢复那个
I think I can recover the data signature
加密广播的数字签名
of that encrypted broadcast.
虽然我还没完全弄明白
I don't understand it yet,
但她就是那样监视我们的
but that's how she was watching us.
给我一小时  说不定能反过来找到她
Give me an hour. Maybe we can start watching back.
有点不对劲
Something's wrong.
这还是在货车那监视我们的镜头
It's the same feed that was watching us in the van.
我放到大屏幕上
Uh, put it on the big monitor.
或许镜头在撞向我们的货车时损坏了
M-maybe the lens broke when the van rammed us.
我希望她坏的不止是这些
I hope she broke more than that.
这是面镜子  我们录下来了吗
It's a mirror. Are we recording this?
现在有了
We are now.
为什么我们会看到这些  镜头在哪里
How are we seeing this? Where's the camera?
是她的眼睛  她就是镜头
It's her eye. She's the camera.
当她闭眼时就切换成后向散射模式
It switches to backscatter when she closes her eyes.
你也像个机器人  你能做到吗
You're a robot. Can you do that?
谁能掌握这些技术
Who has tech like this?
我们没有  至少不像这样的
We don't -- not like this.
没有这么小巧  还能植入人体
Not this small and internal.
这比我所见过的技术超前了十年
That's at least a decade ahead of anything I've seen.
不过既然我见识过了
Though, now that I've seen it,
或许我可以仿制一个  后向散射X光
I could maybe approximate it -- the backscatter x-ray,
一个不会烧焦她大脑的微型接收器
a micro-transceiver that somehow doesn't fry her brain,
一个内置的能量源
an internal power source...
都要很微型  说真的  这...
All miniaturized. Honestly, it's...
-真是太厉害了  -太厉害了
- That's genius. - ...genius.
我们得带她回来
We have to bring her in.
我们得除掉她  她是个武器
We have to take her out. She's a weapon.
我会呼叫总部
I'll call H.Q.,
看能不能叫一队特遣部队支援我们
See if we can bring a task force in to help us.
我们的队伍能应付得来
Our team can handle this.
我明白
I get it.
你觉得有责任  或许你逼她太急了
You feel responsible -- maybe you pushed her too hard.
但她差点杀掉我们三名队员
But she tried to kill three members of our team.
如果她真想我们死  我们早就没命了
If she wanted us dead, we'd be dead.
这次我们走运
We got lucky.
你想再让我们冒一次险吗
You want to risk our lives again?
你说你准备好战斗了  你会支持我
You told me you were ready for combat, that you had my back.
这点毋庸置疑
Don't ever doubt it.
但你为了这个女孩宁愿置队员于危险之中
But you are defending this girl at the expense of the team.
因为我们要保护自己人
Because we protect our own.
恕我冒昧  长官  她不是我们的一员
With all due respect, sir, she's not one of our own.
你们看
Guys.
为什么她还要请求许可
Why does she have to ask for permission?
我可以睡觉吗
待命
她不是在被监视
She's not being watched.
她是被控制了  我们得找到她
She's being controlled. We have to find her.
我们轮流监视这个视频
We'll take shifts watching the feed.
迟早她会看到一些
Sooner or later, she'll look at something
能给我们线索透露她在哪里的东西
that will clue us into her location.
我先来看着
I'll take the first watch.
我只是来知会你一声
I just wanted to give you a quick update.
她还在酒店里  所以...
She's still at the hotel, so...
目前进展就这么多
And that's the update.
真是混乱的一天  不是吗
It's a pretty weird day, huh?
我们就像被困在一个面包车型的糖果罐里
It's like we were trapped in a van-shaped pinata.
那件事确实不该发生
That should never have happened.
没关系
It's okay.
那远比看到爸爸妈妈
It wasn't nearly as terrible
在楼下吵架要好多了
as watching mom and dad fight downstairs.
那也不该发生
That shouldn't have happened, either.
后悔加入我们了吗
You regret coming along?
这是个冲动的举动  即便对我来说
It was pretty impulsive, even for me.
我到现在也不太了解你
I still don't know much about you...
也就知道你非常看重老物件
Except for you value really old stuff.
还有你也看重我
And you value me.
很长时间没有人那么对我了
First person to do that in a long time.
所以我认为你看人还是挺准的
So I happen to believe you're an excellent judge of character.
如果你认为应当再给这个女人一次机会
If you think this woman deserves a second chance,
那我们就应该给她
we should give it to her...
虽然她曾试图杀掉我
...even though she tried to kill me
而且我也挺讨厌她的
and I kind of hate her guts.
-菲兹  -怎么了
- Fitz. - What?
-发生了什么  梅在哪  -我不知道
- What happened? Where's May? - Uh, I don't know.
她之前在盯着传送过来的影像
She was watching the transmission.
阿玛多尔一定是睡了
Amador must be sleeping.
回放一下
Play it back.
托多洛夫大厦  用感应卡到德耳塔5区  九点
看  她又收到了一条消息
There. She got another message --
托多洛夫大厦
Todorov building.
等等  停一下
Wait. Stop.
能把镜头拉近到收据上吗
Can you get closer on that receipt?
卡波哈·波吉坦  皇冠丽晶酒店
该死的  梅
Damn it, May.
卡波哈·波吉坦  皇冠丽晶酒店
叫醒其他人
Wake the others.
那些监视你的人  能监听到声音么
Whoever's monitoring you, do they have audio?
不能
No.
但他们会通过面部识别
But they'll use facial recognition
认出你是神盾局的特工
to determine you're a S.H.I.E.L.D. agent.
那我就不自我介绍了
So I don't have to introduce myself.
-是科尔森让你来的么  -不是
- Did Coulson send you? - No.
他为你感到惋惜  我不会
He feels sorry for you. I don't.
我要把你带回神盾局
I'm bringing you into S.H.I.E.L.D.
你会得到公平的审判  不会害及他人
You'll get a fair trial, and no one else gets hurt.
你完全不知道  是吧
You have no idea, do you?
我们知道你受命于人
We know that you receive orders.
那你就该知道一旦他们看到你
Then you know that once they see you,
能活着走出去的人就只有一个了
only one of us gets to walk out of here.
他们有失败保险机制
They built in a fail-safe.
我杀了你  或者他们杀了我
Either I kill you... or they kill me.
你应该躺在床上
You should have stayed in bed.
你好  阿奇拉
Hello, Akela.
你现在安全了
You're safe now.
缓一缓
Give it a minute.
我刚用强力的树眼镜蛇毒素弹射中了你
I hit you with a powerful dendrotoxin.
我眼睛里有一个致死开关
There's a kill switch in my eye.
为什么我的管理人还没有触发它呢
Why hasn't my handler blown it yet?
你的管理人只知道你和梅特工打了一架
As far as your handler knows, you fought agent May,
你们全都倒下了  然后你醒了
you both went down, then you got up
离开宾馆  继续你的任务
and left the building to complete your mission.
-怎么会  -我们劫持了视频信号
- How? - We hijacked your feed.
我们的一名特工戴着一副模拟
One of my agents is wearing a set of glasses
你的植入物的眼镜
mimicking your implant.
现在  反馈回去的是他的所见
Right now, it's transmitting his point of view
而不是你的
as if it was yours.
眼镜甚至包含反向散射图像
It even has backscatter imaging.
我从接头人那里接到消息了
I get messages from my handler.
我们也能收到
We're receiving those, as well.
我们的特工正在去往托多洛夫大厦的路上
My agent's on his way to the Todorov building --
在我们替你解除失败保险装置的同时
Completing your mission while we disable the fail-safe
帮你完成任务
in your eye.
我保证
I promise.
他们看不到你
They can't see you.
没事的  阿奇拉
You're okay, Akela.
看着我
Look at me.
他们监视你多久了
How long have they been monitoring you?
很多年了
Years.
你为什么要这么做  科尔森
Why are you doing this, Coulson?
我想知道为什么一张感应卡能值三千万
I need to know why a prox card is worth $30 million --
不是
No.
你为什么这么做  为什么帮我
Why are you doing this? Why are you helping me?
你不是应该教训我吗
Where's the "I told you so"?
我现在不会那样了
That's not me anymore.
你还活着我很高兴
I'm just glad you're alive.
要是我做好自己的工作
Vanchat would have never caught us
凡切特就不会抓到我们了
if I'd just done my job.
我应该听你的话
I should have listened to you...
按照你说的去信任我的团队
Trusted my team the way you insisted.
如果我听进去了
If I had...
他们现在可能还活着
they might still be alive.
这是哪里
Where are we?
托多洛夫大厦
Todorov building.
我觉得这是研究用的  不是军方的
I think it's research, not military.
这里看起来像监狱
Looks like a prison.
无线操作了吗
We wireless yet?
好  准备分离
Yep. Ready to detach.
别看我  得让他们以为是她
Don't look at me. They need to think you're her.
天呐  超级间谍竟然怕痒
And, oh, my God, super spy is ticklish.
你是怎么逃出来的
How did you manage to escape?
没有
I didn't.
遇上交火  被击晕
Got caught in a crossfire, went down.
醒来时在什么伤员验伤分类处
Woke up in some half-assed triage bay,
这只眼睛瞎了
blind in this eye.
然后自己在一个铜矿下面的
Spent the next four years alone in a cage
牢房里过了四年
at the bottom of a copper mine.
我们找过你
We looked for you.
有消息说你被带去了山西省
Heard rumors you'd been taken to Shanxi Province.
后来终于有只小队来了
When a team finally came,
开始我以为是神盾局  但是
I thought it was S.H.I.E.L.D. at first, but...
他们是谁
Who were they?
我现在都不知道  但他们很有组织纪律性
Don't know, even to this day, but they were organized.
他们把我带去了一家诊所
They took me to a clinic.
给我做了很多次手术
I had multiple surgeries.
直到有一天我两只眼睛都可以看到东西
Until one day, I could see out of both eyes again.
意识到他们真正的所作所为前  我一直很感激
I was so grateful...until I realized what they'd done.
有人监视你
Somebody was watching.
我的一举一动
My every move.
他们给我发第一条消息时我才知道
I had no idea until they sent the first message.
然后任务就开始了
Then the assignments started.
大多数情况下是让我偷东西
Mostly, it was "Steal this,"
跟踪别人或者闯进什么地方
"Follow him," "Break into there."
我开始不想理会他们
I just tried to ignore them.
但是不理他们就会有疼痛感
But when I did, I'd get this pain,
就像电刺激的偏头痛一样
like an electric migraine.
失败保险
The fail-safe.
这是委婉的说法
Polite way of putting it.
现在想想在牢房里待的那几年
Now, when I think about my years in the cage...
我反而很想念
I miss it.
我希望我能回去
I wish I could go back,
自已一个人  好好睡觉
be alone, sleep in peace.
我知道你很累  但我需要你的帮助
I know you're tired, but I need your help.
如果你想知道感应卡的事
If you want information on the prox card,
那就太不走运了
you're out of luck.
没有情报你无法执行任务
You can't go on missions without intel.
信息是支离破碎传给我的
It comes in pieces --
一个名字  一个地址
a name, an address.
地点确认
进入德尔塔五区
这样活着真是太难受了
It would suck to live like this,
一直在想是不是有人在监视
wondering if someone's watching.
测试后向散射
Testing backscatter.
可以了
Good to go.
记住  我不能看你  更不用说帮你了
Remember, I can't look at you, much less help you.
知道了  也不指望你帮我
Got it. Don't count on you for help.
我会一直监视的
I'll be watching.
拜托  阿奇拉
Come on, Akela.
你从来没见到过那些人吗
You've never spoken to or met anyone in person?
没有
No.
只通过那个英国人发给我的信息来联络
Only contacts are the messages I receive from the Englishman.
英国人  你的管理人吗
The Englishman -- your handler?
你怎么知道他是英国人
How do you know he's English?
他的用词
The way he refers to certain things.
说电梯  他用的是"lift"而不是"elevator"
He uses "lift" Instead of "elevator,"
汽车后备箱  他用"boot"不用"trunk"
"Boot" Instead of "trunk."
回想那些信息
Think about the messages.
你记得些什么
What else do you know about him?
他应该四十岁左右
He's late 30s, early 40s.
经常用一些过时的说法
Uses dated references --
不说"闪存盘"  说"磁盘机"
"Disk drive" Instead of "Flash drive,"
说缅甸的时候用"Burma"而不是"Myanmar"
"Burma" Instead of "Myanmar."
缅甸军政府于1989年将国名改成了"Union of Myanmar"
他打字水平如何
How's his typing?
不怎么样
Clumsy.
经常打错
Makes a lot of mistakes.
手指粗  可能比较魁梧
Thick fingers, maybe heavyset.
我都不记得你有多厉害了
I forgot how good you are.
长官  我们这边准备好了
Sir, we're ready down here.
菲兹和西蒙斯做好手术准备了
Fitz and Simmons are prepped for surgery.
随时都会开始
It should be any minute now.
记住  你的手是男人的手
Remember, you have man hands,
刷卡时候别盯着看
so don't look when you scan the card.
我知道
I know.
沃德到那里了  我们时间很紧
Ward's on-site, so we don't have much time.
要快点把她的眼球拿出来
To remove her eyeball.
我其实不是很擅长眼科手术
Yeah, ocular surgery is not really my field of expertise.
没办法  阿奇拉眼睛里有个致死开关
We've got no other choice. There's a kill switch inside Akela.
里面可能是毒药  也可能是炸弹
Could be a poison, could be an explosive.
无论是什么  一旦沃德被抓住
Either way, if Ward's caught,
他们就会立刻杀了她
they'll kill her instantly.
长官  你要去哪
Where are you going, Sir?
去找出幕后黑手
To find out whose finger's on the trigger.
接近德耳塔3区
Approaching Delta 3.
小心  有镜子
Careful! Mirror.
不用你帮忙
Don't need your help.
管理人肯定就在附近
Handler's definitely local.
能知道他从哪里发出讯号吗
Any idea where he's transmitting from?
这片区域里某个地方
Somewhere here.
他每发一条信息  我们就追踪得更近一步
Every time he sends a message, we get closer.
有消息就用第3频道告诉我
Keep me updated on comm 3.
我出去行动
I'm headed out now.
你可以留在这里监视
I'll track him down if you want to stay here
我去抓他
and oversee the op.
谢谢  但这家伙  我来
Thank you. This one's mine.
-之前那...  -去吧  找到他
- And about earlier... - Go. Find the guy.
手术过程中你可能得给我一些反应
I may need your feedback during the operation,
所以我不得不将局部麻醉剂
which means I have to inject a local anesthetic
注射进你的眼睛  不能给你做全麻
into your eye rather than putting you under.
随你
Whatever's necessary.
好吧
Right.
那我们开始吧
Let's begin, then.
我来
Let me.
目标确认  准备行动
他们说"目标"是什么意思
What do they mean, "target"?
肯定没好事  特别是对那个目标来说
It's never good, especially for the target.
但愿只要打晕他  不用杀了他
Let's hope it's a knockout and not a kill.
你还是出来吧
You should get out of there.
都走到一步了
I've come this far.
无论怎样我都要完成
I'll finish, whatever it takes.
勾引他
快帮我
Help.
我没听错吧
I'm sorry.
你是在求我帮你吗
Did you say, "Help"? Because a minute ago,
刚才你不是不要我帮忙吗
You said you didn't want or need my help.
那是在他们要我色诱这家伙之前
That was before they asked me to go all Mata Hari on this guy.
我直接把他敲晕算了
I'm just gonna knock him out.
沃德  等等  我们可能需要他们来通过下一道门
Ward, wait. We may need them to get through the next door.
记住  说的是勾引  不是杀死
Remember, it said seduce, not kill.
我觉得他应该不喜欢我这一型的
I don't think I'm his type.
让我看看
Let me see.
随便理的头发  胡子拉碴
Cheap haircut. 5:00 shadow.
好吧  我猜你们应该都是直的
Nope. Odds are you guys play for the same team.
那就用兄弟情深那一套
You're gonna have to bromance him.
聊聊运动  伏特加  维秘女模什么的
Talk sports, vodka, the victorianov secret catalog.
友好一点  沃德特工  一定要友好一点
Be friendly, Agent Ward. Can you be friendly?
还有  请不要死
Please don't die.
[外语]
出示你的身份证件
昨晚的比赛怎么样
你的身份证件
好像落在家里了
昨晚玩疯了  遇到两个乌克兰姑娘
根本没睡够
你懂的  对吧
对吗
Da?
看来不懂
Guess not.
现在怎么办
What now?
你要从这些人里面抓一个吗
Are you supposed to grab one of these guys?
任务完成
好运
他们又发了一条消息
They just sent another message.
科尔森  他离你很近  只隔了几个街区
Coulson, he's close -- only a few blocks from you.
就在胜利广场的某处
He's somewhere in Victory Square.
再发一条消息就可以锁定他的具体位置了
One more message should lock in his precise location.
知道需要保镖干什么了
Figured out what I needed the guard for
要他的密码
his password.
没准我能黑进去  给我一分钟
Maybe I can talk you through a hack. Just give me a minute.
没时间了
No more minutes.
跟我在建筑南头碰面  越快越好
Meet me on the south side of the building, A.S.A.P.
明白
Gotcha.
哪边是南边啊
Which way is South?
[外语]
还没有弄出来吗
Please tell me it's out already.
就快了
It's mostly out.
-出什么问题了吗  -没有
- What's wrong? - Nothing.
但是菲兹博士得上前帮忙了
But Dr. Fitzy needs to step in now.
这是他的专业领域  不是我的
This is his area of expertise, not mine.
菲兹
Fitz.
好吧
All right, then.
看起来  动力源和致死开关
Most likely, both the power source
都在这个眼球里面
and kill switch are located within the eye itself.
那么应该如何断开它而不触发开关呢
So, how to disconnect without triggering the kill switch?
我知道怎么做了
I know what to do.
我只需要搞清楚一件事
I just need to clarify one thing.
好了  我们走
All right, let's go!
-沃德  -干什么
- Ward. - What?
你听起来气喘吁吁的
You sound winded.
-是不是时机不对  -有点
- Is this a bad time? - Little bit.
我这边也有点麻烦
Well, not so good for me, either,
我现在手上拿着一个还连着线的
Considering I'm holding a still-attached prosthetic eye
随时可能爆炸的假眼
that could explode at any second.
线是暴露的还是屏蔽的
Are the wires exposed or shielded?
现在就剪  现在就剪线
Cut it now. Cut the wires now!
怎么了
What's happening?
没事儿
Oh, no problem.
沃德解释了一下操作手法
Ward explained the sitch.
朝你来了
Coming your way.
我不懂你什么意思
I don't know what that means.
我们走
Let's go.
也许他一启动致死开关就离开了
He probably left as soon as he threw the kill switch.
定位目标
大约位置
胜利广场
他还在  离你20米远
He's there, 20 meters from you.
我想我发现他了
I think I've got him.
-打扰了  先生  -抱歉  我迟到了
- Excuse me, sir. - I'm sorry, but I'm very late.
我是神盾局的
I'm with S.H.I.E.L.D.
天啊
Oh, god.
他以前是军情六处的军官
He was a former MI6 officer
几年前销声匿迹了
who fell off the grid a few years ago.
我的管理人和我一样被困住了
My handler was as trapped as I was.
这就是说真正的威胁依然存在
Which means the real threat's still out there.
神盾局还在努力破译
Big S.H.I.E.L.D.'s still trying to decipher
黑板上写的东西
what was written on that chalkboard.
没人见过那种东西
Nobody's ever seen anything like it.
有些人觉得可能是外星人写的
Couple of people think it might be alien --
也许是等式
Possibly an equation.
如果它价值三千万  一定很重要
Must be important if it's worth $30 million.
我们会搞明白的
We'll figure it out.
你会受到公平审判
You'll get a fair trial.
我打算作证
I plan on testifying.
我有熟人
I know people.
你理应得到第二次机会
You deserve a second chance.
你已经给过我了
You already gave me one.
以后怎么样并不重要
Doesn't matter how it plays out from here.
我自由了
I'm free.
谢谢你
Thank you.
祝你好运
Good luck.
科尔森特工怎么了  他变了
What happened to agent Coulson? He's different.
他放松了一些
Well, he's loosened up a bit.
纽约之战前  他差点丧命
He nearly died before the battle of New York.
但他们对他做了什么
But what did they do to him?
你说什么
I'm sorry?
当我没问
Never mind.
你还要独处一会儿吗
Are you still needing your you time?
为了AC  我当然有时间
There's always room for A.C.
上车吧
Slide on in.
"科尔森特工"或者"科尔森"
What's wrong with... "Agent Coulson"
怎么不好了
or just "Coulson"?
没什么不好  但AC酷多了
Nothing, I guess. A.C.'s just way cooler.
因为你就很酷
'Cause you are -- cool.
很少有人会做出那种决定
Not many people would have made that call
给阿玛多尔第二次机会
to give Amador a second chance.
我自己也有过
I got one.
只有把这种机会再给别人才算公平
Seems only fair I extend the same opportunity to others.
我明白你为什么喜欢这里面了
I see why you like it in here.
是啊  这就像我的货车
Yeah. It's kind of like my van.
不过没有那些想闯进来的流浪汉
Without all the bums trying to break in.
我不怀念那个
I don't miss that.
这里更加安静
It's more peaceful here.
知道无论发生什么事  都有人会支持我
It's also cool knowing that someone has my back...
这感觉很好
no matter what.
安静很好
Peaceful's good.
《神盾局特工》马上回来
We'll be back in a moment.
叫牌
I call.
再加一百
And raise 100.
你知道我怎么知道我会赢你的吗
You know how I know I'm gonna beat you?
通过输掉吗
By losing?
你有破绽
You have a tell,
一种心理抽搐  让我知道你在虚张声势
a psychological tic that lets me know you're bluffing.
如果我仔细观察你
If I watch you carefully...
对不起  等等
Oh, sorry. Hang on.
你知道如果我这样做的话  不但会看到沃德的牌
You know if I do this, that not only will I see Ward's cards,
还会看到你的裸体吧
but I'll see you without any clothes on?
我退出  你赢了
I fold. You win.